## Senior Process Engineer



# Karoon Pleeram

Gender: Male Nationality: Thai Date of Birth: 2 Nov. 1992 Marital Status: Single

□ kpleeram@gmail.com

**4** +66-95-491-7891 **♦** Rayong, Thailand

#### CAREER OBJECTIVE

1. Project Engineering

2. Process Engineering

I'm seeking a position in the petroleum and petrochemical field where my excellent analytical, technical and management skills can be utilized to improve the company's profitability

#### ABOUT ME

I have been working in area of engineering design and project management in chemical plant more than 3 years. I'm very committed to my assignment and hardworking, enthusiastic about learning skills and gaining various experiences. I have the ability to work well under pressure, still maintaining quality of service and prioritizing effectively

#### **EDUCATION**

2011-2015: Bachelor of Engineering (B.Eng.) Petrochemicals and Polymeric Materials, Faculty of Engineering and Industrial Technology, Silpakorn University. GPA 3.78 (1st Class Honors)

#### PROFESSIONAL SKILLS

English (TOEIC: 785/990)			
Microsoft Office		•	
AutoCad			
ProII			
DCS CentumVP (YOKOGAWA)			
IFS			
PI ProcessBook			

#### PERSONAL SKILLS

Team Work	
Management	
Leadership	
Multitasking	
Communication	• • • • •
Service Mind	
Prioritization	

## REFERENCE

#### Asso. Prof. Achanai Buasri,

Department of Materials Science and Engineering, Faculty of Engineering and Industrial Technology, Silpakorn University. Tel.: +66-88-661-0333

## Expect Salaly: Negotiable

### **WORK EXPERIENCE**

#### Feb 2016-Present: Asia Silicones Monomer Ltd.

(Asia Silicones Monomer Ltd. is a subsidiary of Shin-Etsu Chemical Co., Ltd. Japan)

#### Project/Engineering/Reliability Department

1 Feb 2016 – 31 Mar 2019 : Process Engineer

#### 1 Apr 2019 – Present

- : Senior Process Engineer
- 1. Perform new project, reliability management on process engineering and safety
- Conduct all project works in timely manner and budget control with good quality according to company management by objective.
- Coordinate and assist Project team for implement, commissioning, startup and shut down activities
- Project document control of receiving, registration, distribution and filling of all project technical document.
- Review conception of the improvements change in the plant for cost saving, yield and quality improvement, energy efficiency improvement, waste and pollution emission control, capacity expansion including debottlenecking from the process improvement section before launch the project
- Verify and provide necessary information for Plant Change or modification in term of Process Design
- Check and Update P&I Diagram, Interlocking, and Safety Shut Down systems
- Review designated major equipment document received from the selected vendor prior to purchase.
- Review PFD, P&ID, Plant Layout, Equipment Data Sheet and Drawings (e.g. Equipment drawing, Steel Structure, Piping GA, 3D model and Isometric drawing) prior to construction
- 10. Team conduct Process Safety Management (PSM) related Management of Change (MOC), Pre-startup Safety Review (PSSR), Process Hazard Analysis(PHA)
- 11. Member of HAZOP study for new process or modification process
- 12. Responsible for construction permit, expansion operation permit, operation test run permit and permit relate IEAT and Thai regulation
- 13. Support technical information related to BOI's Investment Promotional Privileges to ensure the Company get great benefits under BOI.
- 14. Coodinator for preparation of Initial Environental Examination (IEE) report submit to IEAT for expansion project
- 15. Experience as user of process instrumentation DCS (YOGOKAWA).
- 16. Experience as user in plant information system, PI system
- 17. Internal auditor for ISO9001:2015

#### **Project Reference**

#### Upgrading Project #2

- Heat recovery of distillation column
- Installation off gas recycle unit
- Installation waste gas regeneration unit
- Feeding gaseous to reaction unit
- Expansion of laboratory room
- Intsallation of HCl gas analyzer
- Heat recovery of reactor effluent
- Installation of new gas compressor
- Installation of new distillation column
- Construction of site storage tank
- Advance Oxidation Process for waste water treatment plant

#### Upgrading Project#3

- Installation of grinding unit
- Distillation tray revamping
- Installation of new distillation column
- Installation of intermediate tank
- Additional water removal step for final product
- Installation of cooling water tower
- Installation of plant air dryer
- Debottleneck of sulfuric acid regeneration unit
- Additional residue bottom cooler
- New MM plant

#### Renovation Project

- Installation of combustible gas unit
- Installation of exhaust gas treatment unit
- Installation of raw material and steam generation unit
- Installation of HCL distillation unit

## Senior Process Engineer



## Karoon Pleeram

Rayong, Thailand

#### May-June 2014: Vinythai Public Company Limited

#### **Student Internship**

- Trainee in Chlor-Alkali plant as process engineer.
- Finding critical exchangers in cooling water systems.
- Doing Hydraulics calculation in Chlor-Alkali plant.
- Doing heat and mass balance calculation on each heat exchanger .
- Identifying problem, cause and offering solutions.

#### Publication

A facile route for the synthesis of reduced graphene oxide (RGO) by DVD laser scribing and its applications in the environment-friendly electrochromic devices (ECD), Journal of Optoelectronics and Advanced Materials Volume: 19 Issue: 7-8 Pages: 492-500 Published: 2017

### <u>Oversea Experience</u>

#### 6-9 Dec 2017: KOCH-GLITCH, INDIA

- Distillation column tray inspection
- Learning about distillation column tray installation and site inspection
- Koch-Glitch factory plant tour for tray, packing and demister fabrication

#### 21-27 Apr 2018 : MERSEN, FRANCE

- Final inspection (Pneumatic test and visual check) for poly block and poly tube graphite heat exchanger
- Factory tour for graphite heat exchanger fabrication and assembly

#### 3-6 Oct 2018: EARTHTECHNICA CO., LTD. JAPAN

- Final inspection (visual and dimension check, air leak test, no load running and function test) for roller mill(grinding machine)
- Factory tour for Crushing and Grinding machine fabrication and assembly

## Training Course & Certification

- The safety officer in supervisor level (a)1.56-013) Certificate No. SS-0483/59: NPC S&E 17-18 Mar 2016
- Hazardous Materials (Hazmat) Specialist (un59-01633):
- Department of industrial works 26 Dec 2016
- **Process Safety Managrment Course:** 
  - NPC S&E 22-24 Feb 2017
- **CentumVP operation course :** 
  - Instrumention & Automation Education Center (YOKOGAWA) 20 Mar 2017
- Clad Materials and Duplex Stainless Steels Seminar:
  - Materials Technology Institute 27 Apr 2017
- Interpretation of ISO 9001:2015 requirement training course:
  - Bureau Veritas 28 Aug 2017
- ISO 9001:2015 Internal Auditor training course:
  - Bureau Veritas 29 Aug 2017
- **Hazop Study Course:** 
  - NPC S&E 14-16 Mar 2018
- **Professional Project Management:** 
  - Thailand Productivity Institute 22-23 May 2018

### HOBBIES

Running, Photograph, Reading